I posed a certain puzzle in a recent
video and based on a couple comments I
realized that I could have been clearer
about what makes this puzzle tricky the
question starts by supposing that you
have a disc with radius one and you
cover it with a whole bunch of strips
when I say strip here I mean a region
that's Bound by two parallel lines and
the quantity that you'll care about is
the width of that strip the distance
between those lines the question is
supposing that your strips completely
cover the disc what is the smallest
possible value for the sum of all of
those widths for example if you just
used a bunch of parallel strips then the
sum of all of the widths would be the
diameter of the circle which is two Now
spoiler alert it turns out that two is
the smallest that you can get and a
couple commenters claimed that they
don't see the point this is obvious
parallel strips should be optimal CU
otherwise you would have some kind of
overlap and overlap is clearly wasteful
that would be true if we were trying to
minimize the total area that these
strips have in that case overlap is
necessarily a waste of area but that's
not the challenge the tricky part here
is that the width of a strip is not
proportional to the area it's perfectly
possible to have a very fat strip near
the edge of the circle with a bigger
width but a smaller area than a thinner
strip near the center of the circle so
for all you know there might be a clever
covering that has a little overlap here
and there which trades off an
inefficient use of area for a more
efficient use of the total width the
challenge is to find find a rigorous way
to prove that this is not possible that
the total width of the strips really
cannot be lower than the diameter of the
circle it's really not an obvious fact
and if you appreciate this it makes the
solution that we cover in the main video
all the more beautiful